Guide to the Maurice Allais Collection, 1945-2003 and undated RL.11078
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Maurice Allais collection
1945-2003 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Allais, Maurice
RL.11078
6.5 Linear Feet 5 boxes
Collection consists of article offprints and monographs by and about economist Maurice Allais. It includes a range of published scholarship written by Allais, along with a small amout of lecture notes and reference articles about his life and work.
Arrangement
Materials are grouped into subseries: Articles by Allais; Articles about Allais; and Lectures. All materials are arranged alphabetically within those subseries.
Biographical / Historical
Maurice Allais (1911-2010) was a French economist who won the Nobel Memorial Prize in Economics in 1988. He worked almost exclusively in French, researching decision theory, monetary policy, and behavioral economics.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Maurice Allais collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2015 from Allais's daughter, Christine Allais.
Related Materials
A significant portion of the original Allais Collection was separated for individual cataloging in Rubenstein Library. Consult the library's catalog for more information.
Collection Overview
Collection contains article offprints and monographs by and about economist Maurice Allais. Materials are listed alphabetically within 3 subseries: Articles by Allais, Articles about Allais, and Lectures by Allais. The first two subseries include publications and clippings from assorted journals, newspapers, and other periodicals. The Lectures subseries contains drafts from Allais's visit to the Thomas Jefferson Center for Studies in Political Economy in 1959.
Economists -- France; Economics -- Periodicals; Economics -- History; Allais, Maurice; Thomas Jefferson Center for Political Economy
- Articles by Allais, 1
  - Abondance ou Misere. Propositions heterodoxes pour le redressement de l'economie Francaise (Bulletin des Transports et du Commerce), 1946 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "L'Allais Effect" et mes experiences avec le pendule paraconique 1954-1960 (Memoire redige pour la NASA), 1999 Nov. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    C-6083
  - Allais Paradox (The New Palgrave. A Dictionnary of Economics), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    C-4588
  - Allais' Rejoinder (Theory and Decision), 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allais' Restatement of the Quantity Theory: Comment by Michael R. Darby (The American Economic Review), 1970 June (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allocution de Maurice Allais (Allocutions prononcees lors de la remise de l'epee [d'academicien] de Marcel Boiteux le mardi 29 mars 1994 a la Pyramide de Louvre) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allocution de Maurice Allais de l'Academie des Sciences Morales et Politiques, Prix Novel de Sciences Economiques (Remise a Thierry de Montbrial de son epee d'academicien. Allocutions prononcees a l'occasion de la remise de l'epee ) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allocutions de Monsieur Andre Giraud, Ministre de l'Industrie et du Professeur Maruce Allais a l'occasion de sa retraite administrative (Centre d'Analyse Economique Ecole Nationale Superieure des Mines de Paris et Centre National de la Recherce Scientifique), 1981 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allocutions de Monsieur le President Pierre Masse et du Professeur Maurice Allais a l'occasion de la remise du Grand Prix Guido Zerilli Marimo de l'Adademie de Sciences Morales et Politiques, le mardi 15 mai 1984 (Annales des Mines), 1984 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aspects Economiques de la Federation Europeenne (La Federation, Libres Opinions), 1947 Aug. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Rapport presente au Congres de Montreux (aout 1947) de l'Union Europeenne des Federalistes
  - Aspects Economiques du federalisme (Bulletin des Transports), 1947 Dec./1948 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Au dela du laisser-fairisme et du totalitarisme (Nouvelle Revue d'Economie Contemporaine), 1950 May (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - L'Avenire de la communaute Atlantique (Bulletin Sedeis. Futuribles), 1964 Nov. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Le Bilan d'une politique et les Conditions de survie du monde libre (Monde Nouveau), 1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Les bouleverserments a l'Est. Quelques certitudes dans un ocean d'incertitudes (L'Europe en formation), 1990 Spring (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Capitalisme et Collectivisme (Le Liberalisme. Troisieme Seminaire de la Pensee Liberale), 1970 Nov. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Caracteristiques comparees des systemes de l'etalon-or, des changes a parites libres et de l'etalon de change-or (Les Fondements philosophiques des systemes economiques. Tire a part. B. - Le Systeme monetaire international), undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Cardinal Utility. History, Empirical Findings, and Applications. An Overview (Theory and Decision), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Les Causes de l'inflation et ses beneficiaires. Les Faux-Monnayeurs (Le Monde), 1974 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    10/29/1974
  - Les Conclusions d'une etude faite a l'Universite de Paris-X. Chomage et augmentation des charges sociales (Le Monde), 1981 June (Box 1, Folder 2)
    1981, June 14-15, copy of newspaper article
  - Chomage et charges salariales globales (Le Monde), 1981 June (Box 1, Folder 2)
    1981, June 14-15, manuscript of article
  - Le Chomage et l'ordre public (L'Ordre public), 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ce quit doit arriver arrive. La Pensee de Jacques Rueff et la Crise d'aujourd'hui (Commentaire), 1997 Spring (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Economies et societes. Classes sociales et civilisations (Cahiere de l' Institut de Science Economique Appliquee (I.S.E.A.)), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Comite pour une Union Federale Atlantique. (Publisher unknown), undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Declaration/Manifeste pour une Union Atlantique
  - Le Comportement de l'homme rationnel devant le risque: Critique des postulats et axiomes de l'Ecole Americaine (Econometrica, Journal of the Econometric Society), 1953 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Concept of Money. The Creation of Money and Purchasing Power Through the Credit Mechanism and its Implications for Growth and the Income Distribution (Centre d'Analyse Economique (C.N.R.S.)), 1976 Apr./May (Box 1, Folder 3)
    No. 3329
  - Le Concept de monnaie, la Creation de monnaie et de pouvoir d'achat par le mechanisme du credit et ses implications (Essais en l'honneur de Jean Marchal/Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Concepts of Surplus and Loss and the Reformulation of the Theories of Stable General Economic Equilibrium and Maximum Efficiency (Foundations of Economics), undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Les Conditions economiques d'une societe libre (Revue des Travaux de 'Academie des Sciences Morales Politiques et Comptes Rendus de ses Seances), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Les Conditions de l'efficacite sur le plan international (Institut Universitaire de Hautes Etudes Internationales), 1969 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Les Conditions de l'efficacite dans l'economie (Centro studi e ricerche su problemi economico-sociali (CESES)), 1967 Sept. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    IV Seminario Internazionale, Rapallo, 12-14 Settembre 1967
  - The Conditions of Efficiency in the Economy (Economia Internazionale), 1968 Aug. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Les Conditions de l'expansion dans la stabilite sur le plan national (Revue d'Economie Politique), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Les Conditions Monetaires du developpement economique. Fascicule III,1 (Universite de Paris X, Faculte de Droit et des Sciences Economiques, Diplome d'Etudes Superieures de Sciences Economiques), 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Les Conditions Monetaires du developpement economique. Fascicule III,2 (Universite de Paris X, Faculte de Droit et des Sciences Economiques, Diplome d'Etudes Superieures de Sciences Economiques), 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Les Conditions Monetaires de developpement economique. Tableaux et graphiques. La Formulation Hereditaire de la demande de monnaie, du taux de l'interet et de l'offre de monnaie. Fascicule III,3 (Universite de Paris X, Faculte de Droit et des Sciences Economiques, Diplome d'Etudes Superieures de Sciences Economiques), 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Les Conditions Monetaires de developpement economique. Tableaux et graphiques. Les Conditions Monetaires de la croissance. Fascicule III,5 (Universite de Paris X, Faculte de Droit et des Sciences Economiques, Diplome d'Etudes Superieures de Sciences Economiques), 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Les Conditions premieres de toute action economique. L'Extension des Services de Documentation Economique et la Reforme des Comptabilites privees (Humanisme Economique. Bulletin de Liaison), 1938 May/June (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - La conference europeenne de Westminster et les problemes economiques de l'Europe (Bulletin des Transports. Commerce - Economie politique), 1949 July (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - La Conjoncture potentiellement instable de l'economie americaine (Il Politico), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Considerations preliminaires a la reconstruction economique du monde. Genese d'un monde nouveau (Publisher unknown), undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - La Construction Europeenne dans le contexte d'aujourd'hui. Pour une reelle Communaute Culturelle, Politique et Economique Europeenne (Banque Generale du Luxembourg), 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Construction of Europe and Eastern Countries in Today's Context. From the Europe Twelve to the Great Europe. Speech (Third European Construction Symposium. Building a Wider Europe), 1991 Apr. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - La Construction de l'Europe (Bulletin des Transports. Commerce - Economie politique), 1948 July (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Contributions a la economique vue d'ensemble 1943-1978 (Centre d'Analyse Economique/Centre National de la Recherce Scientifique) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Contribution a la table ronde sur les contraintes economiques exterieures, organisee par les Annales des Mines (Annales des Mines/Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique), 1984 Mar (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Controle des changes (Publisher unknown), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - La Convertibilite et la Liberation des echanges (Nouvelle Revue d'Economie Contemporaine), 1956 Apr. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Coordination des Transports. Le Probleme de la coordination des Tranports et la Theorie economique (Bulletin du P.C.M.), 1947 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Le Credit et la Creation de monnaie complements au chapitre VI du fascicule III,2 les conditions monetaires du developpement economique (Centre d'Analyse Economique), 1973 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Credit Mechanism and its Implications (Arrow and the Foundations of the Theory of Economic Policy/Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique 1984), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Customs Unions and Trade Agreements (Encyclopaedia Britannica), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    From the fifteenth edition of Encyclopaedia Britannica
  - La Declaration du 16 septembre 1959 (Res Publica. Revue de l'Institut Belge de Science Politique/Tijdschrift van het Belgisch Instituut voor politieke Wetenschappen), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Defense du polytechnicien (L'Aurore), 1959 Dec. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Edition speciale RTA
  - Determination of Cardinal Utility According to an Intrinsic Invariant Model (Recent Developments in the Foundations of Utility and Risk Theory/Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique 1984), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Deux communications a l'Academie des Sciences sur le test de Schuster. Extraits des Comptes Rendus des seances de l'Academie des Sciences, 13 mai 1957 et 23 decembre 1957 (Collection de Centre d'Econometrie) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Deux conditions fondamentales d'un jeu efficace de la concurrence. La Suppression du laisser faire et la Stabilite monetaire (Publisher unknown), undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Discours prononces le 13 mars 1979 a l'occasion de la premise de la medaille d'or du centre national de la recherche scientifique au professeur Maurice Allais par Madame Alice Saunier-Seite, Ministre des Universites (Annales des Mines), 1981 Mar./Apr. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Les Documents Franco-Europeens. Economiques - Politiques - Sociaux (Societe Franco-Europeenne pour l'etude et la creation des institutions federales), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Doit-on reconsiderer les lois de la gravitation? (Perspectives X), 1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Doit-on reconsiderer les lois de la gravitation? Anomalies du mouvement du pendule paraconique a support anisotrope (Fusion), 1998 Nov./Dec. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Echanges et controverses (Revue D'Economie Politique), 1978 May/June (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Includes Lettre a Maurice Allais and Response a Claude Ponsard
  - Echanges et politique commerciale (Economie de la Federation Europeenne (Movimento Federalista Europeo 10)), 1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Economics as a Science (Cahiers Vilfredo Pareto. Revue Europeenne d'Histoire des Sciences Sociales), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Economics as a Science (Etudes et Travaux de l'Institut Universitaire de Hautes Etudes Internationales), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Economic Aspects of Federal Union (Freedom Union), 1949 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Economic Obstacles to Union (Freedom Union), 1949 May (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Economic Science of Today and Facts: A Critical Analysis of Some Characteristic Features (Revolutionary Changes in Understanding Man and Society), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Economic Science of Today and Global Disequilibrium. A Critical Analysis of Some Characteristic Features (Centre d'Analyse Economique), 1989 May (Box 1, Folder 12)
    International Conference on Global Disequlibrium, McGill University
  - Economic Surplus and the Equimarginal Principle (The New Palgrave. A Dictionnary of Economics), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    C-4589
  - The Economies of Eastern Europe in Today's Context. Prolegomena to a Realistic Policy (International Association of Department Stores. General Assembly), 1990 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    C-4997
  - L'Economie des infrastructures de transport et les fondements du calcul economique (Revue D'Economie Politique), 1989 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Economie pure et rendement social (Annales des Mines et des Carburants), 1945 Jan./Feb. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - L'Economie Sovietique est-elle efficiente? (Nouvelle Revue de l'Economie Contemporaine), 1950 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - L'Economique en tant que science (Revue D'Economie Politique), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - L'Economique en tant que science (Etudes et Travaux de l'Institut Universitaire de Hautes Etudes Internationales), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - L'Efficacite de l'economie americaine (Les Etudes Americaines. L'Economie Americaine), undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The Empirical Approaches of the Hereditary and Relativistic Theory of the Demand for Money: Results, Interpretation, Ciriticisms, and Rejoinders (Economia Delle Scelte Pubbliche. Journal of Public Finance and Public Choice), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Entretien avec Maurice Allais, prix Novel de sciences economiques, 1988. (Magazine CFTC Syndicalisme), 1991 Dec. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The Equimarginal Principle. Meaning, Limits, and Generalization (Rivista Internazionale di Scienze Economiche e Commerciali), 1987 Aug. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - L'Esprit de competition (Racing magazine), 1990 Mar./Apr. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Etude theorique des conditions generales de l'amenagement economiquement optimum de la production, de la distribution et de l'utilisation des combustibles solides. Permiere partie, avec annexes I a V (Annales des Mines. Recueil de Memoires de Documents sur les Industries des Mines Arts Sciences qui s'y Rattachent), 1952 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Issue 5
  - Etude theorique des conditions generales de l'amenagement economiquement optimum de la production, de la distribution et de l'utilisation des combustibles solides. Suite e fin: annexes VI a XIII (Annales des Mines. Recueil de Memoires de Documents sur les Industries des Mines Arts Sciences qui s'y Rattachent), 1952 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Issue 8
  - Editorial: L'Europe et le Federalisme economique (l'Engrais. Journal international), 1948 Sept. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Evaluation des perspectives economiques de la recherche miniere sur de grands espaces. Application au Sahara Algerien (Bulletin Scientifique et Economique du B.R.M.A. Hors Serie 1957) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Les Evenements de mai 1958 et la Situation Actuelle (Rivista Internazionale di Scienze Economiche e Commerciali), 1959 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - L'Evolution demographique de l'U.R.S.S., depuis 1938 (Bulletin des Transports et du Commerce), 1950 July (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - L'Evolution demographique de l'U.R.S.S. depuis 1938 (Nouvelle Revue de l'Economie Contemporaine), 1950 July (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Evils of Nationalism (Freedom Union), 1949 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - L'Expansion economique des pays sous developpes dans le cadre d'une democratie liberale (Rivista Internazionale di Scienze Economiche e Commerciali), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Les Experiences de Dayton C. Miller (1925-1926) et la Theorie de la relativite (La Jaune et la Rouge), 1996 Aug./Sept. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Les Experiences de Dayton C. Miller (1925-1926) et la Theorie de la relativite (Fusion), 1998 Jan./Feb. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Les Experiences de Dayton C. Miller, 1925-1926, et la theorie de la relativite. Responses aux observations des lecteurs. I - III (La Jaune at la Rouge), 1997 June/July (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Issue June/July
  - Les Experiences de Dayton C. Miller, 1925-1926, et la theorie de la relativite. Responses aux observations des lecteurs. IV - VIII (La Jaune et la Rouge), 1997 Aug./Sept. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Issue August/September
  - Explication des cycles economiques par un modele non lineaire a regulation retardee (Metroeconomica. Rivista Internazionale di Economica/Revue Internationale d'Economie/Internationale Review of Economics), 1956 Apr. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Explication des cycles economiques par un modele non lineaire a regulation retardee (Publisher unknown), undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - L'Extension des services de documentation economique et la Reforme des comptabilites privees (Editions de la C.C.C.), undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - L'Extension des theories de l'equilibre economique general et du rendement social au cas du risque (Econometrica, Journal of the Econometric Society), 1953 Apr. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Faut-il Reconsiderer les lois de la gravitation? Nouveaux resultats, bilan et perspectives (Cercle Alexandre Dufour), 1959 Nov. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Faut-il reconsiderer les lois de la gravitation? Sur une nouvelle experience de Mecanique. (Cercle Alexandre Dufour), 1958 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Fondements de l'analyse monetaire et conjoncturelle. Monnaie, Inflation, Croissance, Emploi et Conjoncture. Complements. Fascicule V (Ecole Nationale Superieure des Mines de Paris), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Fondements de l'analyse monetaire et conjoncturelle. Monnaie, Inflation, Croissance, Emploi et Conjoncture. Memoires. Fascicule VI (Ecole Nationale Superieure des Mines de Paris), 1980 June (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Fondements de l'analyse monetaire et conjoncturelle. Les Conditions monetaires d'une economie de marches. Fascicule VII (Ecole Nationale Superieure des Mines de Paris), 1987 May (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Analyse economique. Les Fondements du calcul economique. Complements. Fascicule II (Ecole Nationale Superieure des Mines de Paris), 1968 Sept. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Analyse economique. Les Fondements du calcul economique. Appendices. Fascicule III (Ecole Nationale Superieure des Mines de Paris), 1968 Sept. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Les Fondements comptables de la macro-economique. Les Equations comptables entre quantites globales et leurs applications (Press Universitaires de France), 1954 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Fondements theoriques, perspectives et conditions d'un marche commun effectif (Revue D'Economie Politique), Jan./Feb. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Numero special "Le Marche Commun et ses Problemes"
  - Fondements d'une theorie positive des choix comportant un risque et critique des postulats et axiomes de l'Ecole Americaine (Imprimerie Nationale), undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Fondements d'une theorie positive des choix (Annales des Mines), 1955 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Numero Special
  - Forgetfulness and Interest (Journal of Money, Credit and Banking), 1972 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - La Formation Economique de l'ingenieur (Annales des Mines), 1966 Dec. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - La Formation Scientifique (Revue de l'Amopa), 1997 Sept. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - La Formulation hereditaire et relativiste de la demande de monnaie et du taux d'interet. Conference et seminaire des 5 et 6 mai 1980, Departement d'Economometrie de l'Universite de Geneve (Centre d'Analyse Economique/Centre National de la Recherce Scientifique), 1980 June (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - French Inflation and Growth. Mythology and Reality (Paper presented to the ALEPS' Colloquium on Inflation, December 18th, 1974, Centre d'Analyse Economique C.N.R.S.), 1976 Mar. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    With the collaboration of Jacqueline Allais
  - Frequence, probabilite et hasard. Prix Robert Blanche 1983, Academie des Sciences Morales et Politiques (Journal de la Societe de Statistique de Paris) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Frequency, Probability and Chance (Foundations of Utility and Risk Theory with Applications/Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - The General Theory of Random Choices in Relation to the Invariant Cardinal Utility Function and the Specific Probability Function. The (U, Theta) Model. A General Overview (Risk, Decision and Rationality/Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - The General Theory of Surpluses as a Formalization of the Underlying Theoretical Thought of Adam Smith, His Predecessors and His Contemporaries (Adam Smith Bicentenary), 1990 July (Box 2, Folder 23)
    C-4887
  - The General Theory of Surplus and Pareto's Fundamental Contribution (Accademia Nazionale dei Lincei), 1975 Oct. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Convegno Internazionale Vilfredo Pareto (Roma, 25-27 ottobre 1973)
  - La Gestion des houilleres nationalisees et la Theorie Economique (Imprimerie Nationale), circa 1950 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Grand Prix Annuel Andre Arnoux. Remis a Monsieur Maurice Allais, Ingenieur General du Corps National des Mines par Monsieur le Chancelier de l"Institut Jacques Rueff de l'Academie Francaise (Grand Prix Annuel Andre Arnoux), 1968 Oct. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Growth and Inflation (Journal of Money, Credit and Banking), 1969 Aug. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    American Bankers Association, Conference of University Monetary Economists, Ditchley Park, September 10-13, 1968
  - Growth without Inflation (CME Monograph Series), 1968 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Growth without Inflation (Il Politico), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Growth without Inflation (The Mont Pelerin Society Special Meeting, Tokyo, Japan, September 5th to 10th 1966), 1966 Sept. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - The Hereditary and Relativistic Formulation of the Demand for Money: Circular Reasoning or a Real Structural Relation? (The American Economic Review), 1975 June (Box 2, Folder 25)